Nicolas LOUGE, PMP

Sr. Project Manager

nicolas.louge@gmail.com Toronto, ON cell: 437-344-0624

Bilingual project manager with 8+ years of project management experience and a multi-industry track record of success spanning technology, automotive, and aerospace. Major experience lies in project planning, budget and deliverables tracking, and leading cross-functional teams to ensure on-time and on-budget project delivery. A highly attentive and collaborative project management professional with excellent time management, interpersonal, and communication skills.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Project Manager - Microsoft Canada, Wunderman Thompson, Toronto, ON

Dec 2020 - Present

- Managing the creation, update, maintenance, and compliance audit of a portfolio of 100+ local marketing websites that are used to support and amplify campaigns and events across Canada.
- Creating and updating key performance indicators (KPIs) for web reporting and analytics to build engagement and drive informed marketing campaigns.
- Managed and launched the new version of Microsoft Canada Events (one of the major and most strategic local websites
 of the company) using the latest Microsoft standards in design while ensuring the experience was accessible, responsive,
 and fully bilingual.
- Leading the editorial execution in English and French for Microsoft Canada core evergreen marketing websites around artificial intelligence (AI).

Project Manager - PMO, Safran Landing Systems, Toronto, ON

Aug 2019 - May 2020

- Managed and monitored a multi-million-dollar budget, project plans (tasks, resources, hours), and deliverables of a portfolio of 18 Commuter/Military and Research and Technology (R&T) programs.
- Oversaw resource allocation to ensure efficient project progression and on-time delivery.
- Ran weekly meetings with the program team and relevant stakeholders to ensure all key issues/risks were being addressed, mitigation plans were put in place, and governance processes and standards were being adhered to.
- Delivered ongoing Excel and PowerPoint reporting of key metrics of all programs to the engineering management team to support and coordinate the implementation of strategic direction.
- Facilitated communication across the executive team, program and project teams, chief engineers, and PMO analysts in Canada, France and the UK.

Project Manager, Hubnest, Toronto, ON

Sep 2018 - May 2019

- Launched first two products of parent company's new automotive start-up: Dealer Lingo (automotive marketing assistant) and Carlyzer (inventory management mobile application).
- Oversaw product roadmap, project plan, budget, deliverables, documentation, quality assurance (QA), and delivery (Waterfall and Agile Scrum methodologies).
- Identified a major flaw in the backend architecture of the Dealer Lingo web application during onboarding. I led the rewrite of the entire architecture and shipped the next releases on-time and on-budget until the launch.
- Managed internal and client projects through prioritization planning, coordinated internal/external communication, and continuous improvement of project management processes.
- Developed the recruitment process and interviewing assessment tools to recruit copywriters.

Project Management Consultant. ASI. Paris. France

May 2017 - Dec 2017

- Deployed a visual management software solution (iObeya) to 20+ projects of Bolloré Transport & Logistics's IT department, including process documentation, coaching, and training.
- Managed the relationship with the vendor regarding the billing and the upcoming releases.
- Led project management software (Planisware) and WBS template implementation for Zodiac Aerospace US in California and Texas through updating of program planning requirements, production plans validation, and User Acceptance Testing (UAT).
- Organized and led training workshops across Engineering, Supply Chain, Procurement, Program Management, and Manufacturing departments.

A ... ~ 2010 N/ ~... 2020

Project Manager – Renault Nissan Mitsubishi, MI-GSO, Paris, France

May 2014 - May 2017

- Delivered weekly Excel and PowerPoint reporting of key metrics of vehicle projects sold in China, South Korea, and France to the Engineering management team to monitor project status versus the milestones objectives to provide guidance and to plan strategic action plans.
- Implemented a new cross-functional position for Renault-Nissan-Mitsubishi with a focus on enhanced monitoring tools, robust reporting and continuous KPI improvement for the Project Management Office (PMO) of the Systems Engineering Department.
- Managed a team of 10 project schedulers responsible for project performance tracking and reporting on the project.
- Oversaw project deliverables on the brand's three largest projects while serving as a point of contact on purchasing activities across four international departments.
- Optimized onboarding time by 50% by creating a welcome kit and by launching a new version of Renault's internal knowledge management software for the entire group. A very valuable resource used daily by thousands of employees around the world.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATION

Project Management Professional (PMP), Project Management Institute, Toronto, Ontario

Dec 2018

ESAIP, Graduate School of Engineering, Toulouse, France Master of Engineering degree - IT Project Management

Sep 2008 - Sep 2013

SKILLS

Technical: Planner, Excel, Project, Microsoft Office

Languages: French (native); English (fluent)